<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Aabir Roy</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Aabir Roy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023, Aabir Roy.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First setup of the SWAN system</title>
      <link>/first-setup-of-the-swan-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/first-setup-of-the-swan-system/</guid>
      <description>After a hectic midsem week, The Radio Astronomy Club, BITS Pilani decided to open up the SWAN system and start setup. We scheduled a meet with the IIT Kanpur SWAN team, and they guided us through the process.
To power on a system you require, well, power. However, a small but not so insignificant problem stood in our path - we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the main power plug for the receiver system!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sky Watch Array Network (SWAN)</title>
      <link>/sky-watch-array-network-swan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sky-watch-array-network-swan/</guid>
      <description>The brainchild of Dr. Avinash Despande, the Indian Sky Watch Array Network aims to set up a group of radio telescopes across institutes in India, with the long-term goal of having a country wide radio interferometer which will help in the imaging of FRBs, pulsars and other astronomical sources.
It will significantly enchance Indian observing capabilities in the radio frequencies and also establish a sustainable approach to cultivate and support upcoming generations of skilled radio astronomers in India, enabling them to tackle challenges and spearhead compelling research in the field of radio astronomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup multiple git accounts on a system</title>
      <link>/setup-multiple-git-accounts-on-a-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/setup-multiple-git-accounts-on-a-system/</guid>
      <description>Git is an indispensible part of my workflow. I happen to use git for both my personal and work related projects. However, moving between these accounts can be challenging at times. In order to counter this, we can make use of a feature called conditional includes.
Setup ssh keys To start with let&amp;rsquo;s set up the ssh keys for each of our accounts. Check for any existing ssh keys in the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hi there,
I recently turned 21, and decided to start a blog. I will be updating it, sharing insights into my current work and experiences.
I hope to learn to better communicate my thoughts and ideas and effectively convey them to an audience.
Thanks for stopping by!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
